mike roberts

software engineering manager

☑ miker@miker.org 🛭 🛇 miker.org 🔏 508.579.4478

As a seasoned engineering manager with over two decades of experience leading consumer-facing product teams, I have consistently driven product and technical vision and strategy to achieve results.

My expertise lies in managing high-visibility projects and work streams, particularly advertising, personalization, operations, and machine learning. I am known for my ability to provide constructive and positive feedback, which has consistently motivated and inspired my teams. My leadership approach is characterized by saying the hard things when necessary and ensuring that my engineers grow as leaders and technical experts. As a 'player/coach,' I have the technical expertise to dig into the details when necessary to ensure robust architecture and quality code.

experience

CarGurus Cambridge, MA 2021 - present Senior Manager of Algorithmic Traffic Acquisition

I own the CarGurus teams for recommendations, ad content, ad partner integrations, and ATA devops. My recommendations team, via messaging (email and push) and onsite advertising, is responsible for 26% of CarGurus' revenue. I work closely with the CarGurus data science team to implement and facilitate testing new machine learning models in our recommendations system.

Indigo Agriculture

2019 - 2021 Principal Engineer (Manager and Architect) At Indigo, I managed the back office settlements team and led the way in pioneering

high availability and 24/7 uptime services. As one of Indigo's architects, I introduced reactive patterns and built a widely used message bus to connect our microservices asynchronously, showcasing my innovative spirit.

Salsify Boston, MA 2016 - 2019 Principal Engineer (Manager)

At Salsify, I led the platform services team, developing the shared infrastructure and code used by Salsify's application teams. Notable accomplishments include building an asynchronous job system and the first wave of Salsify's GraphQL APIs.

TripAdvisor Vacation Rentals Boston, MA

2015 - 2016 Principal Engineer

I ported legacy FlipKey and Holiday Lettings systems to a new unified system.

Leaf Holdings Cambridge, MA Software Engineering Manager (Director)

I led the Android and platform teams, enhancing the existing proof-of-concept to scale to 100k transactions per second. I hired dozens of engineers, including a fully remote team in Istanbul. I designed a distributed, eventually consistent data store cohomed on our Android tablets and on AWS.

Smarter Travel Media

Charlestown, MA Software Engineering Manager (Director and Architect) 2009 - 2013

Built and led the Tingo team, spinning up a new online travel agency in 9 months. I led hiring across the STM engineering organization. I ran the architectural review board.

education

Worcester Polytechnic Institute

- BS Theatre
- BS Computer Science

skills

expert

- Kotlin
- Java Ruby
- Postgres • MySQL
- Kafka
- Gradle
- **AWS**
- git
- Terraform

experienced

- Scala
- Python
- Javascript
- Redis
- SQL Server
- Kubernetes
- Packer
- Puppet
- Maven
- SBT
- GraphQL

faq

Charlestown, MA

Star Trek or Star Wars?

• Star Trek

Marvel or DC?

DC

Vim or Emacs?

Vim

Narnia or Middle Earth?

Middle Earth

Kanban or Scrum?

• Kanban, but every team is different

Kirk or Picard?

Janeway